we need to
modify the code we've been given so that
our loop stops executing
if number is between 0 and 10.
number is a variable local to this block
and each time we iterate through our
loop number will be assigned to
a random number between zero and
ninety-nine
remember that the kernel rand method
used here on line
two will return a random integer between
zero and one less than the argument we
passed to it
in this case that's one hundred
so
[Music]
taking this code out of our loop for a
moment let's just run the program
and print out these random numbers
[Music]
and you can see that zero is included in
our output
[Music]
okay so now we can see
how rand is randomly generating these
numbers for
us and they're being assigned to the
local variable number
[Music]
so going back to our loop structure we
know that we need to
break out of this loop if the number
generated by rand
is between 0 and 10.
we can use an if statement and if the
condition that we provide
evaluates to true then we will execute
the reserved word break
and break out of this loop otherwise the
loop will continue
so we need to think about what our
conditional will be
to determine whether the number is
between 0
and 10. there's more than one way that
we could do this but let's start by
using the
comparable between method
and this method takes two arguments the
two integers that we want to look
between
[Music]
and it will return a boolean either true
or false
[Music]
so if our condition returns true we'll
use the reserve word break to break out
of this loop
otherwise we want to keep looping and
generating these random numbers
so let's run our code as is
okay so you can see that our number was
between 0 and 10
it was 5 which we output to the screen
and then we broke out of our loop and
our program finished running
let's run the program one more time okay
and now you can see that
we had to loop through several times
before
the random number generated was between
zero
and ten and finally the number generated
was five
so our if condition evaluated to true
and we broke out of the loop
so this program is working according to
the problem requirements
if we wanted to we could remove lines
six and seven
and place our break statement on the
same line as the conditional
again you'll see that our program works
as expected and stops looping when
number is equal to one
we could also determine whether our
number is between zero and ten
in a few different ways
for example we can use comparison
so if our number is greater than or
equal to zero
and our number is less than or equal to
then we want to break out of our loop
now in this case
i would actually move my break statement
back into a longer if statement just to
make things more readable
[Music]
okay and again we see our program
generating these random numbers until
it's reached
a number between 0 and 10. so that works
as well
another solution might be to create a
range
from 1 up to 10 inclusive
and call the include method which will
return a boolean
and pass in number as an argument
and again we iterate through until we've
reached a number between
0 and 10 7 in this case
and then we break out of our loop and
the program ends
this logic here just checks whether the
given range
includes the argument passed to the
method
there are multiple ways to test the same
logic
and as you learn more about ruby you'll
learn a little bit more about the
different methods available to you